Oliver Baxandall

Software Engineer, Garrison Technology Limited, London

Experienced in full stack development, continuous integration of software projects and finding things to do. Working in numerous roles of this nature has promoted a deep love of coffee, a fascination for anything to do with technology and a DIY attitude. An active individual maintaining balance with an assortment of hobbies, including work as a professional magician, 3D-printing of designed CAD projects and rock climbing.

✓ oliver.baxandall@gmail.com

+447564912273

in linkedin.com/in/oliver-baxandall



github.com/Ollivanders

EDUCATION

BSc Natural Sciences - Computer Science and Economics Durham University - 1st Class Degree

09/2016 - 06/2019

- Cryptography, Blockchains, V&A Reality, Game Theory, AI and Procedural Generation.
- Social Secretary for the frisbee team, responsible for organising external events with other universities and maintaining high spirits during and between games.
- President of Durham University Dodgeball Team, organising weekly training sessions and competitive games to introduce people to the game.
- Winner of Most Ambitious Hack and Best Use of Google Cloud Platform at Durhack2019 for producing an automatic, parameter-based running route plotter.
- Received the 2019 Natural Sciences award for Outstanding Achievement.

A-level Qualifications

Colchester Royal Grammar School

09/2014 - 06/2016

- 5-A* and 2-A grades, including Mathematics, Economics, Biology & Physics.
- Financial Director of the Young Enterprise Company 'Tangent'.
- Founder of Coffee Soc., a relaxed society ending the year with 68 members.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Solution Management Garrison Technology Limited

08/2020 - Present

Waterloo, London

- Lead integration of AWS into existing systems for automated cloud deployment, using Python CDK and CloudFormation for staged security deployments.
- Use of Docker for automated testing of pipeline deployments. Incorporation into virtual appliances for controlled package upgrades between releases, expediting fluid correction of security concerns when using third-party/open-source software.
- Created and manage a developer environment through dotfile installation, allowing consistency and sharing between developers. CI into WSL2 and as an .ova for Linux deployments in VMware and Virtualbox, for use by existing and new colleagues.

Distruptive Cyber Security Researcher

BT Research and Innovation, Emerging Security Paradigms

06/2018 - 08/2020

Adastral Park, Ipswich

- Blockchain analytics, incorporating Apache Spark machine learning and Scala to analyse and visualise/classify complex data sets, automated in Python.
- Nova Development of a polymorphic blockchain, web-based visualisation tool for forensics, maintenance and deployment of blockchain based applications. Full stack development project using NodeJS frontend, Flask API and Postgres database integration for custom exploration of blockchains, previously incongruous structures.
- Owner of patents encapsulating VR, continuous authentication, layer-mapping and machine-user display, contributing towards the BT Security portfolio.

Production Research Analyst Vinelake, the Internet of Business

05/2017 - 08/2017

The Internet of Business, leverages internet of things and vertical technology to businesses via formal events, newsletters and social media

- Responsible for contacting speakers for events and researching IoT home space and applications of blockchain technology for enterprises, keeping an up-to date blog on the subjects for the company and their clients.
- Assisted in the development and setup of a communications network, connecting to a final interface in Microsoft Teams and SharePoint.

SKILLS

Python ReactJS SQL

VIM

Docker

UNIX

Distributed Systems

Gitlab Persistence

Positivity

REPORTS

The Key Determinants in the Price of Bitcoin: a Story in Speculation (06/2017 - 07/2018)

- Sponsored publication by the Laidlaw Leadership Scholarship Program at Durham University.
- Connected social media trend data with price volatility resulting in a concluding assessment of valuation dependencies and vulnerabilities of Bitcoin, uniquely modelling the quantitative price movements.

Automated Assessment of Procedurally Generated Graphical Level Content (06/2017 - 04/2018)

- Researching techniques for systematic random generation in C++ and Blueprint in the Unreal Engine.
- Spawns original material for game engines followed by an integrated AI for evaluating and altering the final user-experience or developer environment.
- Applied to on-demand production of game material, a development tool for professionals wishing to experiment with game mechanics and in education as an introductory game development environment.

Simulation of Malware Propagation and Effects in Connected and Autonomous Vehicles (02/2020 - 08/2020)

- Report generated after research contributing to the ResiCAV Autonomous vehicle project, while part of BT.
- Mobius Development culminated into a layer-based mapping tool/application, originally used for simulation of malware in autonomous vehicles using SUMO.
- Founding and maintaining developer of the product, deployed into various applications, such as tracking of COVID contacts and 5G mast arson investigations, with visualisation options for time, location and properties.
- Shortlisted for CogX 2020 AI Product of the Year and winner of E&T's Excellence in Cyber Security Award
- Link: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9231063.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Competed in the UK National chess Giga and Mega Finals (2006 - 2009)

Qualified Rookie Life Guard (2015)

Shortlisted for UK Ninja Warrior (2017)

INTERESTS

Mentalism and Card Magic

3D-Printing

Hardware Hacking

Ultimate Frisbee

Freestyle Gymnastics

Rock Climbing